all right uh we've been going through a
special
book and uh my teacher taught it to me
for 30
years uh he finished it three
times and uh 13 years
ago I promise my students I will finish
it so the good news we're
about almost
90% and uh when we get close to finish
gisha always adds something
more and so uh we're going to do a
special book that's connected
to uh and that will take another seven
or eight years I think
and um so my whole time as a
student uh I was every week I was always
going to hear this
book and I thought uh there shouldn't be
a ending it shouldn't
finish I used to call the book The the
gas station the petrol
station because I will go there and I
will fill up my
car I will fill up my
heart and then I can you know survive
until the next time my teacher teaches
it so it's not a book like in the
school it's an
experience and it's a it's a lifetime
experience and uh when I think about my
teacher so the whole time with him I
always got to go to the
gas and he kept teaching it over and
over
again so I think that's uh what we have
to do also
and a has to come back
to many
time okay and uh we can keep going to
this
book the book is called uh steps to the
poth and it's a each step for the pth to
be a a good person or a happy person
and I'd like to thank Tim and all
ACI Al everyone from
ACI and you guys are doing a good
job uh I think as you can see in in
Asia uh there's about I think there's
about 200,000 students now coming to
this
and they're all learning about the good
heart I don't know what's
vond yeah and so all over the
world uh people are learning about how
to have a kind heart or good
heart and it makes your life very
happy it makes your life very
successful that that thing you saw
that's a business that's a business
C and uh so you can be successful if you
have this Good
Hope and your family life is
good and I I think the most important
thing is you have
fun uh you can have fun okay your whole
life and uh I'm 70 years old this
year and I've been teaching this for 50
years and I have to say it's super
fun and your whole life can be
fun I think somehow that's the most
important
thing so you can be
successful good family life good
business
life but I think the main thing and what
we're going to study this this
week is how they have
fun okay and uh especially we reach the
part about
fun this
week the main
subject is how to have
fun uh in your
life it's
more easy to have fun if you're
successful
okay
uh like if you have uh lots of
income if your family life is
nice so we're going to be covering those
things and uh this
particular subject this
time it's called L
Jong please say
Lord
Lord yeah Lo means here it means good
heart and Jong means like exercise at
the
gym so it's how to exercise your
kindness and it's a nice uh thing you
can do every
day and you can learn and you can go
home and you can use it
okay I met a guy in Shanghai
recently he
uh he asked me do I have time to talk to
him and I said no I I
don't then he he waited by the elevator
in the
hotel when I go in the elevator he come
in you
know then he talks very slow while the
elevator you
know and uh he said I just want to thank
you you
know and I said for what you know and he
said um because of because of what you
taught last
year uh I made $10 million this
year and I'm also very
happy and I just want to thank
you and and I didn't see him again after
that I don't know his
name and it's the same
here okay you're GNA make $10 million
heart and we can learn how to do
it and then you don't have to join um gy
Michael fan club or Alo fan
club yeah and just take it
home and use it and maybe I see you
after 10 years I don't
know and you'll be super
happy and super
successful so it's not like a it's not
like a religious thing
really just share with you something
that I was
taught and take it home
try
it I went with my wife I made a big
mistake uh I went with her to buy the
jeans bad
idea yeah those stores you know they
don't have chair for the
guys and you have to stand up wait
and don't tell her I told you
[Music]
okay she tried 42 pairs of pants
on over two hours
standing hey an guess how many pairs she
bought
perfecto
so everybody's
different uh the pants that fit
me they maybe they don't fit
you you know everybody has different
PS and that's a good
thing so I'm gonna teach you share with
[Music]
you
uh some nice pants that I learned
about and try it out
you know and if if it fits
you uh then wear you know and if it
doesn't fit
you go look for some other place it's
okay so let's have fun
together definitely there are some
things in here that you will
enjoy and it will make your life very
helpy
and that's that's the goal of why we are
here and so let's
start I'm going to give you a
list it's 11 different
things and we're going to talk about it
for one
week and it's 11 different things to
work on your
heart and that's the whole
week and starting
tomorrow I will call on
people
randomly
and if you can tell me the
11 I will give you one
okay and then every day I do five or 10
people
okay so I'm Bri bribing
you so usually we bribe the police and
things like
that but uh in this class the teacher
bribe
you so there's
11 ways to make your heart
happy and we're going to learn about it
the whole
week we're gonna learn how to meditate
on
it guess what when you meditate what do
you do with your
[Music]
eyes you close
them okay so you cannot look at the
computer
you have to remember this
11 then you can do a really sweet
meditation and that's the old tradition
2,000 years
old uh just learn 11
things uh keep it in your
heart people ask me G when do you
meditate you so busy
I meditate on the airplane I meditate in
the
car I do a lot of meditation in the
buo okay any place I have some free time
you
know and those 11 are here you know this
is my my cell
phone you know I just close my
eyes and uh if you're sitting in that
special place it's it's going to fall in
the right place it's
okay then uh you can
meditate okay here's 11
okay and I you got to remind me
tomorrow and I really will give bribes
okay okay number
[Music]
one treat people equal
treat people
equally very simple that's the
beginning every person is equally
important to
me and I will treat them
equal okay so tomorrow when I call on
you you don't have to give 10y year
commentary
just say
equal number one
equal okay number one number
two they are your
mom so you can say equal Mom I don't
care
equal and
Mom and this is a little difficult but
it's
okay
you used to be someplace
else before you came into your
mom okay we don't know
where I also don't know
where it's like a Darkness I cannot see
there but I know uh I was
someplace uh if you have a
dice
and it has six numbers on
it and you roll it a billion
times and you will get lots of ones you
will get lots of twos you will get lots
of Threes
okay if you can come here once then you
can come here twice if time is
infinite the odds are
infinite you you rolled the dice billion
billion billion you cannot
count if you can be alive
once then must be you were alive
someplace before
then because time time and SP infinite
infinite
okay you have you have lived infinite
times and each person in this
room has been with you infinite
times
and they have been your mother
infinite you came out of my body a
million
[Music]
times at least make me some juice or
something so number
two try to
understand everybody's been your
mom all the kids in this room all the N
have have been my
mom that's so try to understand okay
everyone has been your mom
what number is
that
two okay number
three it's hard to be somebody's mom I
was watching the moms down
here arranging pillows with Grandma I
guess and
uh some Americans think say I don't like
my
mom I say
listen there's a thing called abortion
even anybody can get it you take a
pill to give a
[Music]
baby is to risk your
life and every woman knows
that your mom risk her life to give you
life and she decided to do
it and she decided your life her life is
not as important as your
[Music]
life then the real work start after the
real
work take care of the kid for 10 years
20 years 60
years so much
trouble a million
troubles I watch my friends have kids
I'm like God how can you do
that just everything
diffic so I don't care how you feel
about your
mom
you cannot deny she risk her life to
give you
money and then she feed you like three
times a day
forever and she kill herself to work for
the
money so you you should think what's
what's the third word what you what are
you going to
use uh
equal
mom too
complicated we call
kindness
kindness okay first
one equal second
one mom then think about how much
kindness they gave
you I don't like my mother she she she
she complain about
me but she she worked so hard for so
many
years okay so kindness is number
[Music]
three I'll give a $100 right
now you got rob you got it it's in the
red it's in the red
wallet okay you're the
man you're you're Santa Claus okay
don't tell me you can't find it no uh
red
purse red purse in the main yeah there
you go it's full it used to be full okay
uh if number three is
kindness Rob then you got to stand up
and waving
[Music]
around and then you
decide Mr hagy
decides who gets to try the
answer wait now I get really upset when
people raise their hand before I ask the
question number
one equal number
two mom number
three number four
get Rob choose Rob Cho number
four no you choose the person you have
to go stand next to the person and wave
the money in the
face
Rob tell her if she gets it right you
can split
it n I'm kidding I'm kidding I'm K
what's number
four
up to you
rob good payback yeah yeah yeah yeah all
right
woohoo you pay her
[Music]
back if someone risk their life to give
you your
life
and you don't try to thank
that you're a really strange
person okay so you know tell your
mom thank you Mom you know what can I do
for you how can I pay you
back what number is that number
four okay now uh it's a little bit
different and we go to it there's a
meditation inside the
meditation uh and I I I don't think you
can
guess number
five is uh everybody has equal right to
be
happy so it's similar to number
one it's similar to what number one but
you can say equal right to
Beav everybody has equal
right number
five by the way this list was made 1,300
years
ago nice okay I'll show you the picture
of the the author
later
uh
number
six taking care of myself first is a bad
idea that's number
six how do you want to say it shortly
I selfish
bad
yeah I mean if if I have equal right if
everyone have equal right to be
happy then why G Michael always take the
first
CH why why I'm staying for the prayer
after this
talk I saw all the churos in the
back
okay then everybody has a right to those
jles but human
nature I I I will take one
first okay that's not respect equal
rights we we all have equal children
rights number
six it's wrong to take the first one
it's wrong to take care of your self
first that's number
six
uh
Rob now if you know what is number
six you can guess number seven and make
$100
up to you up to you you
choose he's going to be the most
unpopular take care of other people
first
yeah
yeah yeah number
six when you try to take care of
yourself first there's a lot of
trouble number
seven just relax and take care of other
people
first and that's the main
fun it's much more fun to give a CH than
to take a
CH and that's that's one of the most
valuable things we are learning in this
week everybody wants to be happy
everybody wants to be
successful I don't know what you guys
were doing during coid but I made 20
more organizations
okay and um the income is crazy that's
why I can give away
$100 but the the main
essence is give to other people
first take care of other people
first then really everything you want it
will come like like T
tsunami I have fight today with
Ellie uh how to put enough money in how
to put a lot of extra money in the
bank
you know and I'm like wow what's going
on the money came and she didn't she
couldn't put it in the bank there's some
problem then if you take care of other
people
first you will have this
problem okay it's strange
right uh by the way there's a
[Music]
famous quality of the Buddha
we were translating it in ben craver's
book Buddha knows what's real and Buddha
knows what's not
real like
that the real situation
n how it
lies name Kim he knows the real
situation and he knows what's not the
real situation
I'll give $300 nah you can't
guess forget
it what's not the real
situation if I give more I will have
[Music]
less if I give more I will have
less
that's a lie it's not
true but every human being believes
it gu don't ask me to give too much then
I won't have
enough yeah don't you know how you get
things the only way to get things is to
give
them
that's
reality you want
things give them
away you you don't want
things if do you want to have shortage
for your whole life and not be able to
pay your
rent then don't help other
people and you will always be
struggling got it it's the opposite
okay so uh what number we're on number
seven eight no but seven six
was if you take care of yourself
first it's a big
mistake it's the best way to have not
enough
money
or
I care more about TR money you
believe where's
iron maybe we change my Cafe to a
cheria okay okay all right then number
seven it's a good thing to take care of
other
people take care of other people
first if if you're
smart take care of other people first
okay by the way you young
people
Hol I so I I went to the I went to
register for voting or
something they asked me what's your
birth
year I said
52 then I said
1952 the guy look at me like is it
1852 so you you young
people you have a chance this is
valuable
information I wish I knew this when I
was young like
you then I'll be so successful and so
happy take care of other people
first that's the best way to take care
of
yourself okay
and I I go all around the world all all
year I'm just like I live in the
airplane my friends told me G when you
retire we will put an airplane in front
of your house we will take off the tires
and we will put so so you can feel
comfortable CU you can go sleep in
[Music]
airplane and it's the same story every
country please just try
it you're
young if you make a good habit
now you got to be super there's going to
be 6,000 people a
even when you sing The Rock and Roll
bad they're like
wow take care of other people
first and everything will be good okay
all right now what
number so
[Music]
slow
when other people have
trouble put yourself in their
chair so we call change yourself with
them okay like if Al those having
trouble then gishi Michael has to put
himself in
Aldo's
body
to feel how Aldo
feels you can say
compassion uh you can say
empathy but learn how to have
compassion okay number eight I don't
care just say
compassion even if you say
comp or
Ash I don't don't
care okay put yourself in the other
person's
body in your
imagination and see how they
feel that's number eight okay number
[Music]
nine
practice
love so what was number
eight come
come okay eight is
come and nine is
Love Now what's the
difference compassion wants to take away
other people's
trouble love wants to make them happy
I always think about a kid on a
bicycle when they fall
down and they hurt their
knee what's the first thing mom has to
do you know like that you know you know
like that's number
eight then number
nine oh here I don't have candy
have a candy okay you don't first you
fix the
hurt then you give the candy you don't
give the candy if it's
hurting okay so first feel the
pain say I feel your
pain and then do something nice give
them
something number eight is
comp nine is love
love okay nine is
love I'm gonna just do it I'm gonna do
it if you do it this way tomorrow you
get
100 and it's not one person I want to do
like 10 people
tomorrow why can't I do it because I do
this and that's why I have the okay all
right uh number one
by the way no papers
tomorrow the eyes tomorrow are
[Music]
closed don't write it on your
hand
okay it's I'm not stupid like your
school
teacher okay number one in
number two my mom number
three kindness yeah number
four repay nice number
five equal right you and me number
six stop taking care of yourself
first then number seven is
easy take care of other people first
number
eight
come
Ash okay
compassion yeah when other people hurt
hurt than
you then nine is
automatic love give the candy give them
candy oh my gosh this the easiest money
you ever made
tomorrow by the way tomorrow's class is
also open
okay uh also open
online uh you don't have to pay we we
don't charge for these
classes if you want to do the extra
activities we ask you to pay
[Music]
for but tomorrow everything's free okay
so just come and come with your 11
tomorrow all right and it's all it's all
free tomorrow online
also all
right by the way I used to be in the
diamond
business for 19
years I built the largest diamond
jewelry company in the
world quar billion dollars every
year Warren Buffett bought the
company now guess what's more
money to teach like this or to have a
diamond
business yeah if I want to make money I
can sell diamond
okay uh we ACI we are not making money
okay we just Mak it
happy make people happy
but I came here on a thing it's called a
airplane when I bought the
ticket I said I'm teaching compassion it
should be
free they said get out of line sir next
person next
person
so you know we have to pay the airplane
and
all nobody's making okay nobody's making
we have
expenses all right number
10 was it number
10 huh what what's
this this says Taiwanese
Mexicans
okay
this is long oh yeah okay this
one uh somebody has to take care of this
world somebody has to take
responsibility for this
[Music]
world number 10 is
responsibility I take
responsibility we saw all this news for
one year about Ukraine people
suffering they are bombing
them and finally uh our group in in
Arizona we contact
them come to come to
Arizona we will pay
everything and we we give you a place to
stay we just bought a new car you
know you know if the if the governments
can't figure it out well godamn we can
figure it
out you just come and stay with us you
know and we'll have fun you know and so
we got two came
already and a mother and her son are
[Music]
coming in two weeks or
something so number
10 I take
responsibility I don't wait for
government
program what if these two ladies died
during the government program
decision okay I'll take care of it
myself if the government with a billion
billion dollars can't figure it out I I
God I do
it okay that's number
10 I'll take care of it by the way it's
very useful at a program
in Via
Prima who's gonna clean up after the
party
tonight I take
responsibility
okay like that okay uh it's not always
International sometimes it's
interal all right somebody I'll take
responsibility all right number
11 and I would like to take
responsibility for every
planet
[Music]
what that I'll take care of the whole
I'll take care of this whole planet
that's number
10 and by the
way I'll take care of the other planets
as soon as they find
them I'll take care I know look right
now it's not
real right now there's not we don't know
where the other planets
are
but it's that infinite thing
again the the planets are
infinite try to understand
something when you say the planets are
infinite there's a planet somewhere
right now where the same halfway bald
guy and the completely bald guy are are
giving a talk right
[Music]
now there's an
definitely and there's a person there
who looks just like
you because the planets are
infinite there's not one person who
looks just like
you
there's countless people who look just
like
you then number 11 is Like a
Prayer look I I can't see that handsome
person who looks just like
me I I I I didn't meet them
yet but the odds are
infinite there must be a person like
that
and number 11
is I take responsibility for them
too I take responsibility for planets
with no number and people with no number
and I take it I sign the contract in
advance okay you can check later my
signature on the
papera there's two guys from
Mars they got two heads and four
legs can they stay at your
house I don't
know but you promised that was number 11
you promised in
guara okay okay I I put the
Contra number 11
every
planet every planet I can't see them
right
now with my
eyes but I can see them with my
thinking you
know is there a lot of churos in the
Next
Room look told you there
is no reason to
lie
you you can see those TRS but with your
third
eye why those Buddhas have
three that's just logic just
logic oh all right can you see those CHS
with your two
eyes no the door's
closed can you see it with your third
eye yeah
gu probably won't lie about
it then we say third
eye then those other people in the
universe other
planets a person who looks just like
you not one
million and you're you're going to sign
a contract
now when I meet you I will take care of
you and I
agree all right got it those are the
11 okay and we spent about two years on
it you guys are lucky because you
finishing one
night it's like Express
train uh Tim what time am I supposed to
stop
Oh I thought
she's
okay okay
um I will finish on time
too all right uh we're gonna start the
class s say
s special G Class
uh whole
[Music]
night
okay are you going to show the book Tim
and
then we're on
naten it's about two pages then uh I'm
going to show you the ancient
book you don't have to learn
it you just have to learn 11
things but
uh we like to teach it word by
word and that you don't have to learn it
I'm planting a seed in your
mind we have a date in the next
life and you're going to learn this
language I'm getting ready
now okay you don't have to think about
it I don't care if you don't look at
it I'm planting a seed for next time
okay we're going to start the
book and we'll just do five
minutes and then we'll continue
tomorrow
[Music]
uh
when you get
sick and when you get
problems it's important to watch your
selfishness
level when we have
trouble when we have
debt when we have some kind of
diseases when we're super
busy then that compassion we for forget
about
it okay when we have
trouble uh we forget about other
people and what he says here
is it's more important when you have
trouble
not to be
selfish okay when you when you don't
have enough
money nowaday people have a Time problem
they don't have money
problem you know I don't have time to
help
you you know so when things
are difficult
when you don't have enough
money when you don't have enough
time and when your body is giving you
trouble I heard a a good friend of mine
has cancer I found out
today then give
more okay when you are
sick when you don't have money
when you don't have
time give
more okay that's that's and then things
will come to don't
[Music]
worry when you think you don't have more
to give you always have more to
[Music]
give and if you get used to giving more
when you don't have more to
give
you will feel so
happy just make a
habit when you don't have more to
give give a little
more and and you will always be a happy
person and you will always have enough
don't
worry uh budha said an interesting
thing Buddha
said
if any
person gives more when they think they
don't have
more and they don't get much more
back then I'm not
Buddha he said it like that then I'm a
liar what did Jesus
say when someone steals your
Co give them your sweater
also
got when someone take your
coat you know don't fight with them say
hey do you need a sweater
also I also have a
sweater so these great people like
Buddha
Jesus they really understand
when you give the last thing you have
when you give your
coat and then the people are still
[Music]
cold then give them your sweater
also don't don't worry about
it okay got it and you will always be
happy and your life will be so like that
video you know okay really I
I it really happened like
that just
give all right uh we'll continue
tomorrow